Guide to the Records of the Office of Vice President for Student Affairs (Marshak) RG.12.0.4
New York University Archives
Records of the Office of Vice President for Student Affairs (Marshak)
1985-2000
New York University Archives
New York University. Office of Student Affairs
Marshak, Margo Post
RG.12.0.4
27.14 Linear Feet in 55 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, and 1 flat-file folder
Margo Post Marshak served as Vice President of the NYU Division of Student Affairs from 1991 to 2001. The Division's purpose is to offer programming, services, and resources to support students while attending NYU. The Records of the Office of Vice President for Student Affairs (Marshak) contain Margo Marshak's work files ranging in date from 1985 to 2000, which include memos, correspondence, meeting minutes/agendas, planning notes, reports, event fliers, and marketing material. Topics include student housing, dining, safety, healthcare, counciling, and relations with various NYU student groups.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in boxes 55 and 56 are restricted.
Material pertaining to individual student records may be restricted in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). Please contact the Archives with specific questions regarding access to such records.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Material was transferred from Margo Post Marshak's office between circa 1998 and 2001. The accession numbers associated with these transfers are 00.007 and 98.019.
Appraisal
The following were removed from the collection: one 3.5inch floppy disk of duplicate material, and 2 cartons of duplicates, Board of Trustee minutes, and publications.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor, which is often in alphabetical runs by file title.
Historical Note
The mission of the New York University Division of Student Affairs is to complement and support the University's academic mission, as well as to provide an enriched quality of life for students in and out of the classroom through supportive programming, services, and resources.
Biographical Note
Margo Post Marshak assumed the position of Vice President for Student Affairs in 1991. She remained in that position until September of 2001 when she left for a post at the University of Chicago.
Scope and Contents
The Records of the Office of Vice President for Student Affairs (Marshak) (1985-2000) document the tenure of Margo Post Marshak who served as Vice President of the New York University (NYU) Division of Student Affairs from 1991 to 2001. These records contain Marshak's work files which document the Vice President's role in projects and responsibilities within her division, as well as University-wide. Materials illustrate the primary responsibilities and student-related issues Marshak was responsible for, including housing, food service, campus security, healthcare, crisis counseling, and interactions with student groups. Topics that were timely to this particular era in Student Affairs include the AIDS Advisory Committee; MMR immunization for students; Bobkin Lane renovations; Southgate Hotel student housing; renovations of fraternity housing at 3-5 Washington Place; a car accident within Washington Square Park with NYU student fatalities; and the building of the new University Health Center. Marshak's files typically include memos, phone call logs, correspondence, meeting minutes/agendas, notes, reports, event fliers, and marketing material.
College students -- Housing -- New York (N.Y.); Universities and Colleges -- Administration; Student affairs administrators; Memorandums.; Correspondence.; Notes (documents); Reports.; Minutes (administrative records); New York University. Office of Student Affairs
- Administrative Management Council, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Admissions, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Affirmative Action, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- AIDS Advisory Committee, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
- Alcohol, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 6-7, Box 2, Folder 1)
- ARAMARK, 1991-1996 (Box 2, Folder 2-5)
- ARA Services, 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 2-6, Box 4, Folder 1-2)
- ARA Services -- Proposal, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- ARA Services -- Competitors, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- ARA Services -- Declining Balances, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Asian Pride, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Astor Place Property, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Benefits, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Board of Trustees, 1995 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Materials are restricted.
- Board of Trustees -- University Life Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 55, Folder 2)
- Bobkin Lane Refurbishments, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Budget, 1992-1995 (Box 5, Folder 2-5)
- Campus Security, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Career Services, 1991-1995 (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
- CCNY (City College of New York) Review, 1990-1992 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Children's Services, 1988-1994 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Commencement, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Committee on an Internationalized Community (CIC), 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
- Committee on Student Residential Housing, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Community Service, 1992-1995 (Box 7, Folder 6, Box 8, Folder 1)
- Community Service Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Computer Information, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Conference Center, 1989-1992 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Controversial Speakers, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
- Council on Community Service, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Counseling Service, 1989-1995 (Box 9, Folder 2-4)
- Daily Events, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Ellis Island, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- EQUAL (Enhancing the Quality of Undergraduate Academic Life) Commission, 1993-1995 (Box 9, Folder 7, Box 10, Folder 1)
- EQUAL (Enhancing the Quality of Undergraduate Academic Life) Residence Hall Life Subcommittee, 1992-1994 (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
- Events Planning, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Faculty Resource Network, 1992-1994 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- FERPA (Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act), 1992-1995 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- FIPSE (Fund for the Improvement of Postsecondary Education), 1992-1994 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Fraternities, 1992-1995 (Box 11, Folder 1, Box 55, Folder 3)
  Materials in box 55 are restricted.
- Fraternities -- Delta Phi, 1993-1994 (Box 11, Folder 2, Box 55, Folder 4)
- Fraternities -- FIJI, 1988-1993 (Box 11, Folder 3, Box 55, Folder 5)
- Fraternities -- FIJI Renovations, 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 4-5)
- Gallatin Arts Festival, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Graduate Counterparts, 1992-1995 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Greek Life Advisor, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 1, Box 55, Folder 6)
- Guest Housing, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Guest Suites, 1992-1995 (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
- Health Education, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Health Insurance, 1993-1995 (Box 12, Folder 6-7, Box 13, Folder 1)
- Health Insurance -- Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 13, Folder 2, Box 55, Folder 7)
- Health Insurance -- Students Maintaining Matriculation, 1993-1994 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Health Insurance -- Surveys, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Health Services -- General, 1989-1994 (Box 13, Folder 5-7, Box 14, Folder 1-3)
- Health Services -- Fees, 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Health Services -- Organization Subcommittee, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Health Services -- Task Force, 1992-1993 (Box 14, Folder 6, Box 15, Folder 1-2)
- House of Blues, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Housing -- General, 1991-1996 (Box 15, Folder 4-7, Box 16, Folder 1-3)
- Housing -- Fall Housing, 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Housing -- Cable TV, 1991-1995 (Box 16, Folder 5-6)
- Housing -- Consultant, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Housing -- Contracts with Non-NYU Groups, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Housing -- Dental School, 1992-1994 (Box 17, Folder 3-4)
- Housing -- Graduate Students, 1992-1994 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Housing -- Maintenance, 1992-1995 (Box 17, Folder 6-9, Flat-file-folder 9)
- Housing -- Occupancy, 1992-1995 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Housing -- Ombudsperson, 1992-1993 (Box 18, Folder 2-3)
- Housing -- Rates, 1992-1995 (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
- Housing -- Reorganization, 1992-1993 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Housing -- Resident Assistants (RAs), 1993-1994 (Box 18, Folder 7-8)
- Housing -- Task Force on Residence Hall Life, 1991-1993 (Box 18, Folder 9, Box 19, Folder 1-3)
- Housing -- Residence Life, 1992-1994 (Box 19, Folder 4-5)
- Housing -- Shortage, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Housing -- Southgate Hotel, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Housing -- Staff, 1992-1996 (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Housing -- Student Information System (SIS), 1992 (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Housing -- Summer, 1992-1994 (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Housing Task Force -- Sylvia Baruch, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 5-7)
- Housing -- Telephones, 1992-1994 (Box 20, Folder 8, Box 21, Folder 1)
- ID Cards, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- International Festival of Puppet Theater, 1990-1992 (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Inter-Residence Hall Council (IRHC), 1992-1994 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Jewish Cultural Foundation, 1991-1994 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Jewish Student Life Organizations, 1991-1994 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Legal Counsel, 1992-1994 (Box 55, Folder 8)
- Lesbian / Gay Student Services, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Loeb Food Court Architect, 1992-1995 (Box 21, Folder 8-9)
- Loeb Operations, 1992-1994 (Box 21, Folder 10)
- Moses Center for Students with Disabilities, 1992-1994 (Box 21, Folder 11, Box 22, Folder 1)
- NYU -- SOS (Supporting Our Schools), 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Office for African-American, Latino, and Asian-American Student Services, 1989-1995 (Box 22, Folder 3-5)
- Office for International Students and Scholars, 1991-1995 (Box 22, Folder 6-7)
- Orientation, 1992-1994 (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Carlos Oyola Scholarship, 1992-1993 (Box 55, Folder 9)
- Parliamentary Debate Team, 1992-1994 (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Playing Fields (Weehawken, NJ), 1992-1993 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- President Oliva Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 55, Folder 11)
- Refund Policies, 1992-1995 (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Registration MMR Immunization, 1991-1992 (Box 23, Folder 5)
- Resource Planning Group, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 6)
- Safety Alerts, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 7)
- School of Continuing Education (SCE) Self Study, 1992-1995 (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Schwartz Plaza, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 9)
- Sexual Harassment, 1992-1993 (Box 23, Folder 10)
- Smoking, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 11)
- John Ben Snow Dining Room, 1991-1995 (Box 23, Folder 12)
- Special Interest Housing Board, 1992-1993 (Box 24, Folder 1, Box 55, Folder 10)
- Special Senate Committee on Faculty-Student Relations, 1990-1992 (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Sports Marketing, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 3)
- Stores, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Student Activities, 1990-1995 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Student Affairs -- Space, 1991-1994 (Box 24, Folder 6-7, Box 25, Folder 1-3)
- Student Affairs -- Staff, 1992-1994 (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Student Affairs -- Staff Meeting, 1992-1995 (Box 25, Folder 5-6, Box 26, Folder 1)
- Student Assistance Center, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Student Clubs, 1992-1994 (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Student Employment, 1992-1993 (Box 26, Folder 4-5)
- Student's Guide to NYU, 1989-1994 (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Student Health Planning Group, 1991-1994 (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Student Health Program Subcommittee, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 8)
- Student Information System (SIS), 1992 (Box 27, Folder 1)
- Student Life, 1990-1995 (Box 27, Folder 2-7, Box 28, Folder 1-2)
- Student Senators Council, 1992-1995 (Box 28, Folder 3)
- Telephone Log, 1993-1995 (Box 28, Folder 4-5)
- Third Avenue North Dining Project, 1994 (Box 28, Folder 6)
- 3-5 Washington Place -- Fraternity Housing Space, 1991-1993 (Box 28, Folder 7)
- 3-5 Washington Place -- Fraternity Vandalism Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 29, Folder 1)
- Tisch School of the Arts -- High School Drama Camp Housing, 1992-1994 (Box 29, Folder 2)
- Total Quality Management -- NYU, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 3)
- Tragedy in Washington Square Park, April 23, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 4)
- Trolley Services, 1992-1995 (Box 29, Folder 5)
- 21 Washington Place, 1994-1995 (Box 29, Folder 6)
- Ultra Violet, 1992-1993 (Box 29, Folder 7)
- Uncle Ezra, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 8)
- University Committee on Student Life Meetings, 1994-1995 (Box 29, Folder 9-11)
- University Relations, 1991-1995 (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
- Vice Presidents' Meeting, 1991-1995 (Box 30, Folder 3-6)
- Village Improvement Planning Committee, 1992 (Box 30, Folder 7)
- Violet Ball, 1992-1993 (Box 31, Folder 1)
- Washington Square Health Services Project Steering Committee, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 2)
- Washington Square News, 1992-1994 (Box 31, Folder 3)
- Windows on Washington Square, 1992-1994 (Box 31, Folder 4)
- Paul Grayson, 1994-1997 (Box 31, Folder 5)
- AIDS, 1985-1993 (Box 31, Folder 6)
- Sally Arthur, 1994-1997 (Box 31, Folder 7-9, Box 32, Folder 1)
- Carl Bender, 1994-1997 (Box 32, Folder 2-3)
- CCNY Background, 1991-1992 (Box 32, Folder 4)
- Center for Music Performance, 1989-1997 (Box 32, Folder 5-8, Box 33, Folder 1-2, Flat-file-folder 9)
- Committee for Overseas Study, 1994-1995 (Box 33, Folder 3)
- Counseling Services, 1991-1995 (Box 33, Folder 4)
- Earth Matters, 1985-1996 (Box 33, Folder 5)
- Faculty Grievance, 1992-1996 (Box 33, Folder 6)
- Kimball Hall, 1995-1996 (Box 33, Folder 7, Flat-file-folder 9)
- Sal Longarino, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 8)
- Questionnaires, 1990-1992 (Box 33, Folder 9)
- Student Loans, 1992-1993 (Box 33, Folder 10)
- Bobkin Lane, 1992-1995 (Box 34, Folder 1-2, Flat-file-folder 9)
- Housing -- Cooper Union Parking Lot, 1995 (Box 34, Folder 3)
- Housing -- Dental, 1995-1996 (Box 34, Folder 4)
- Housing -- Engineering Associates, 1995-1996 (Box 34, Folder 5)
- Housing -- Maintenance, 1993-1995 (Box 34, Folder 6-8)
- Housing -- Off-Campus, 1992-1995 (Box 34, Folder 9)
- Housing -- Special, 1995-1997 (Box 35, Folder 1-3)
- Bob Kivetz, 1993-1997 (Box 35, Folder 4-7)
- Resident Assistant (RA) Selection, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 8)
- Telephone Log, 1996-1997 (Box 36, Folder 1-4)
- Vice Presidents' Meetings, 1995-1997 (Box 36, Folder 5)
- Health Services Planning, 1995-1997 (Box 36, Folder 6, Box 37, Folder 1-4)
- University Health Services (UHS) -- John Patey, Construction Project Management, 1996-1997 (Box 37, Folder 5-7)
- Health Services, 1993-1996 (Box 38, Folder 1-3)
- Health Services -- Architect, 1993-1997 (Box 38, Folder 4-6)
- Measles Immunization, 1989-1991 (Box 38, Folder 7, Box 39, Folder 1)
- Health Services Space, 1992-1996 (Box 39, Folder 2)
- University Health Center (UHC), 1992-1997 (Box 39, Folder 3-7, Box 40, Folder 1)
- Donna Boguslav, 1993-1996 (Box 40, Folder 2)
- Francesca Gany, 1995-1996 (Box 40, Folder 3)
- Association of Lesbian and Gay Faculty, Administrators and Staff (ALGFAS), 1993-1994 (Box 40, Folder 4)
- AmeriCorps, 1994-1996 (Box 40, Folder 5)
- ARAMARK, 1996-1997 (Box 40, Folder 6)
- ATM, 1993-1995 (Box 40, Folder 7)
- Campus Dining, 1996-1997 (Box 40, Folder 8)
- Campus Ministry, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 9)
- Career Services, 1994-1996 (Box 40, Folder 10)
- Center for Music Performance, 1989-1996 (Box 40, Folder 11)
- Classes in Residence Halls, 1992-1995 (Box 41, Folder 1)
- Club Quarters, 1995-1996 (Box 41, Folder 2)
- Coca Cola, 1994-1996 (Box 41, Folder 3)
- Community Service, 1992-1997 (Box 41, Folder 4)
- Student Computing, 1994-1997 (Box 41, Folder 5-6)
- Controversial Speakers, 1994-1995 (Box 41, Folder 7)
- Credit Cards, 1997 (Box 41, Folder 8)
- Daily Events, 1997-1998 (Box 41, Folder 9, Box 42, Folder 1)
- Undergraduate Dean's Meetings, 1994-1997 (Box 42, Folder 2)
- "Dean's Table", 1994-1995 (Box 42, Folder 3)
- Dorm Connectivity, 1996 (Box 42, Folder 4)
- Due Process Procedure, 1993-1994 (Box 42, Folder 5)
- Eighth Street Theater, 1995-1996 (Box 42, Folder 6)
- Emergency Response Planning, 1994 (Box 42, Folder 7)
- Enhancing the Quality of Undergraduate Academic Life (EQUAL) Commission, 1995 (Box 42, Folder 8)
- Events Planning, 1993 (Box 42, Folder 9)
- External Funding, 1992-1994 (Box 42, Folder 10)
- Faculty in Residence, 1993-1996 (Box 42, Folder 11)
- Financial Systems Redesign Project, 1996 (Box 42, Folder 12)
- Fraternities, 1992-1994 (Box 42, Folder 13)
- Gallatin Statue, 1995 (Box 43, Folder 1)
- Health Center Planning, 1995-1996 (Box 43, Folder 2)
- Health Educator, 1995-1996 (Box 43, Folder 3)
- Housing Task Force, 1995-1997 (Box 43, Folder 4-6)
- Housing -- Contracts, 1994-1996 (Box 43, Folder 7)
- Housing -- Deferred Maintenance Program, 1996 (Box 43, Folder 8)
- Housing -- General, 1995-1998 (Box 44, Folder 1)
- Housing -- Grand Union, 1996 (Box 44, Folder 2)
- Housing -- Occupancy / Space, 1994-1995 (Box 44, Folder 3)
- Housing -- Personnel, 1992-1995 (Box 55, Folder 12)
- Housing -- Southgate, 1995-1996 (Box 56, Folder 1)
- Housing -- Summer, 1993-1997 (Box 44, Folder 4)
- Insurance -- Student Health, 1993-1995 (Box 44, Folder 5)
- Interest Rates, 1993 (Box 44, Folder 6)
- International Faculty, 1995 (Box 44, Folder 7)
- Inter Residence Hall Council (IRHC), 1997-1998 (Box 44, Folder 8)
- Kiosks, 1995 (Box 44, Folder 9)
- La Pietra, 1992-1994 (Box 44, Folder 10)
- Local Law 10 / 80 Reports, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 11)
- Mayor of Moscow -- Visit, 1997 (Box 45, Folder 1, Box 56, Folder 2)
  Materials in Box 56 is restricted.
- Multicultural Education, 1992 (Box 45, Folder 2)
- Office for African American, Latino, Asian American Student Services (OASIS), 1994-1997 (Box 45, Folder 3)
- Office for African American, Latino, Asian American Student Services (OASIS) -- Assistant Director Interview Kit, 1996 (Box 45, Folder 4)
- Office of International Students and Scholars (OISS), 1995-1997 (Box 45, Folder 5-7)
- Office of International Students and Scholars (OISS) -- Medical Center Relationship, 1991-1994 (Box 45, Folder 8)
- Parents, 1993-1997 (Box 46, Folder 1)
- Plague, 1991-1992, 1996 (Box 46, Folder 2)
- Refunds, 1995-1996 (Box 46, Folder 3)
- Vending, 1992-1994 (Box 46, Folder 4)
- Senior Week, 1994-1996 (Box 46, Folder 5)
- Student Affairs Staff Meetings, 1993-1996 (Box 46, Folder 6-7)
- Student Affairs Staff / Personnel, 1992-1996 (Box 46, Folder 8)
- Student-Related Problems, 1992-1996 (Box 46, Folder 9)
- Telecommunications, 1991-1996 (Box 47, Folder 1)
- VIP Visitors, 1994-1995 (Box 47, Folder 2)
- Resolved Student Issues, 1993-1999 (Box 47, Folder 3-5, Box 56, Folder 3)
  Materials in box 56 are restricted.
- Village Alternative, 1997-1998 (Box 47, Folder 6)
- University Counseling Center -- "Complete", 1997-2000 (Box 47, Folder 7)
- University Hall Dedication, 1998-1999 (Box 47, Folder 8)
- Computer Committee, 1993-1995 (Box 48, Folder 1, Box 56, Folder 4)
- Office of International Students and Scholars (OISS), 1996-1998 (Box 48, Folder 2-3)
- Student Life, 1995-1998 (Box 48, Folder 4-6)
- University Committee on Student Life (UCSL) / Student Senators Council (SSC) Meeting Files, 1995-1998 (Box 49, Folder 1-3)
- University Health Center (UHC), 1995-1999 (Box 49, Folder 4-5, Box 50, Folder 1-3)
- University Health Center (UHC) Insurance, 1997-1999 (Box 50, Folder 4-5, Box 51, Folder 1)
- Alcohol, 1995-1999 (Box 51, Folder 2-3)
- Price Waterhouse Cooper, 1999 (Box 51, Folder 4-6, Box 52, Folder 1)
- University Health Center (UHC), 1997-2000 (Box 52, Folder 2-7, Box 53, Folder 1)
- Surveys and Statistics, 1993-2000 (Box 53, Folder 3-4)
- Protection Services, 1997-2000 (Box 53, Folder 5)
- Lchow's Building Site Project, 1996-1999 (Box 53, Folder 6, Box 54, Folder 1-3, Flat-file-folder 9)
- Parents, 1995-2000 (Box 54, Folder 4-5)